Register of the Better Homes in America Records
Hoover Institution Archives
Better Homes in America records,
1923-1935
XX395
Better Homes in America
60 manuscript boxes, 13 oversize boxes (39 linear feet)
Hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, press releases, expense statements, clippings, pamphlets, and photographs, relating to home ownership in the United States. Includes correspondence of Herbert Hoover as president, and Marie M. Meloney as organizer, of the association.
Administrative Information
Access
Microfilm use only (except for box 57 that has not been microfilmed).
Acquisition Information
Acquired.
Alternative Form Available
Also available on microfilm (64 reels).
Accruals
Increments may have been received since this finding aid was prepared. Please check Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat to find the full extent of the collection.
Historical Note
Private organization to encourage individual and community efforts at home improvement in the United States.
Scope and Content Note
The Better Homes Movement was initiated in 1922. This plan for encouraging local communities to undertake demonstrations for home improvement was developed by Marie M. Meloney, then editor of the national circulation magazine The Delineator. The first national campaign was held from October 9 to 14, 1922. The second campaign was shifted from fall to spring and was scheduled for June 4-10, 1923. Both early campaigns were supervised by Marie Meloney.
In the beginning, The Delineator was the chief organ of the movement, which gained national attention and support readily. Marie Meloney organized an Advisory Council to guide the work. In this connection, she took some of her ideas for an extensive voluntary effort for the improvement of housing throughout the country to Herbert Hoover, then Secretary of Commerce, and enlisted his support and membership on the Advisory Council. The Council was made up of distinguished men and women from government, business, and professional fields. The movement was endorsed by President Warren G. Harding in a letter to Secretary Hoover in February 1923. The demonstration week of June 1923 had the support of the governors of 30 states and of the territories of Alaska and Hawaii.
Before the end of 1923, the Advisory Council had recognized the need for independent organization, longer-term status, and more adequate financing. The Delineator relinquished all connection with the movement, and Better Homes in America was incorporated as a non-profit, educational organization in the state of Delaware on December 22, 1923, with the following five individuals as original members: Marie M. Meloney, Herbert C. Hoover, Christian Herter, John M. Gries, and John A. Sellards. Mr. Hoover agreed to serve as President of the new organization, and Mr. Coolidge, then Vice President of the United States, became Chairman of the Advisory Council. A request for support was made to the Laura Spelman Rockefeller Fund, which provided a grant to finance operations for three years. This grant was later extended. Offices were established in Washington, D.C., where the organization functioned until 1933, when it was moved to New York City. Dr. James Ford, Associate Professor of Social Ethics at Harvard University, was engaged to direct the work of Better Homes in America, beginning in 1924, and continued in that capacity until 1935.
The mission of the Better Homes in America was to help American families make their homes more convenient and attractive. As more and more communities participated in the local campaigns, activities were concentrated mainly in the following divisions: home improvement, community improvement, urban-rural relationships, and dissemination of information on housing and homemaking subjects. Efforts in these areas were made through the annual campaigns and demonstrations, cooperation with national, state, and local organizations, press coverage, and publications. The Better Homes Manual was published by the University of Chicago Press in 1931.
By 1935 the number of communities participating in the Better Homes Week campaigns had reached 10,000. Due to lack of funds, however, the corporation of Better Homes in America had to be liquidated. The research and publications work was transferred to the Housing Research Foundation at Purdue University, Indiana. The momentum of interest by the Better Homes Week campaigns continued through 1937, despite the fact that there was no organized backing for the work during the last two years.
After the corporation was dissolved, the right to handle all future activities of Better Homes in America was turned over to the Housing Research Foundation at Purdue University. Most of the historical office files were sent to the Hoover Library at Stanford University.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the repository's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Home ownership--United States.; Housing--United States.; United States.; United States--Social conditions.; Cities and towns--United States.
Other Index Terms Related to this Collection
Meloney, Marie M.; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964.
Container List
- Microfilm Reel Content Guide
  Downloadable PDF file of the Microfilm Reel Content Guide
- Founding Documents, 1923-1935. (Box 1)
  Correspondence, memoranda, minutes of meetings, reports, and other documents relating to the creation and dissolution of Better Homes in America, Inc. Arranged alphabetically by physical form
  - General. One bound volume containing correspondence, minutes of meetings, and other documents relating to the creation and dissolution of Better Homes in America, Inc., 1923-1935 (Folder 1: 1-2)
  - Certificate of incorporation, 1923 (Folder 1: 3)
  - Constitution and by-laws, 1930 (Folder 1: 4)
  - Endorsement by Warren Harding, 1923 February 5 (Folder 1: 5)
  - Minutes of meetings of the Executive Committee, 1923 (Folder 1: 6)
  - Statements
    - General, 1923 (Folder 1: 7)
    - Hoover, Herbert C., 1924-1928 (Folder 1: 8)
- Board of Directors File, 1924-1935. (Box 1-3)
  Correspondence, reports, memoranda, speeches and writings, and other material generated by the Board of Directors. Arranged alphabetically by physical form
  - General
    - Undated (Folder 1: 9)
    - 1924 (Folder 1: 10)
    - 1925 (Folder 1: 11)
    - 1926 (Folder 1: 12)
    - 1927-1929 (Folder 1: 13)
    - 1930-1931 (Folder 1: 14)
    - 1932 (Box-folder 2: 1)
    - 1933-1934 (Folder 2: 2)
  - Correspondence
    - Ford, James, 1925-1932 (Folder 2: 3)
    - Gilbreth, Lillian M., 1930-1934 (Folder 2: 4)
    - Halbert, Blanche, 1932 (Folder 2: 5)
    - Hoffman, Helen Duey
      - 1932 (Folder 2: 6-7)
      - 1932-1933 (Folder 2: 8)
    - Meloney, Marie M., 1926 (Folder 2: 9)
    - Taylor, James S.
      - 1927-1930 (Folder 2: 10)
      - 1930-1935 (Folder 2: 11)
  - List of Board of Directors members (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - Speeches and writings
    - Ford, James, 1925-1931 (Folder 3: 2-3)
    - Halbert, Blanche, 1924-1932 (Folder 3: 4-5)
  - Subject file
    - Finance Committee, 1931 (Folder 3: 6)
    - Office of the Treasurer, 1933 (Folder 3: 7)
    - Rockefeller Foundation, 1930 (Folder 3: 8)
- Advisory Council File, 1923-1935. (Box 3-6)
  Correspondence, memoranda, forms letters, lists, and speeches and writings of the Advisory Board. Arranged alphabetically by physical form
  - Correspondence
    - Abbott, Grace, 1929 (Folder 3: 9)
    - American Civic Association, 1933-1935 (Folder 3: 10)
    - Arnold, Sarah Louise, 1925-1928 (Folder 3: 11)
    - Barnes, Julius H., 1924-1929 (Folder 3: 12)
    - Brown, Edwin H., 1923-1930 (Folder 3: 13)
    - Davis, James J., 1929 (Folder 3: 14)
    - Delano, Frederick, 1925-1931 (Folder 3: 15)
    - Farrand, Livingston, 1924-1929 (Folder 4: 1)
    - Gries, John M., 1923-1934 (Folder 4: 2)
    - Harriman, Oliver, Mrs., 1928-1929 (Folder 4: 3)
    - Herter, Christian, 1924-1935 (Folder 4: 4)
    - Hoover, Herbert C.
      - 1923-1926 (Folder 4: 5)
      - 1927-1932 (Folder 4: 6)
    - Ihlder, John, 1924-1932 (Folder 4: 7)
    - International Federation of Home and School, 1929 (Folder 4: 8)
    - J. Horace McFarland Company, 1929-1932 (Folder 4: 9)
    - Jardine, William, 1925-1928 (Box-folder 5: 1)
    - Kelly, Edgar Stillman, Mrs., 1925-1929 (Folder 5: 2)
    - King, Francis, Mrs., 1929 (Folder 5: 3)
    - Lake, Elise A., 1933-1935 (Folder 5: 4)
    - Meloney, Marie M.
      - 1924-1930 (Folder 5: 5)
      - 1931-1934 (Folder 5: 6)
    - Metropolitan Life Insurance Company, 1923-1929 (Folder 5: 7)
    - National Housing Association, 1929-1932 (Folder 5: 8)
    - Parker, William Stanley, 1930-1935 (Folder 5: 9)
    - Payne, John Barton, 1923-1929 (Folder 5: 10)
    - Pratt, Harriett B., 1924-1935 (Folder 5: 11)
    - Prichard, Adelia, 1924-1929 (Folder 5: 12)
    - Redford, W. C., Mrs., 1925-1928 (Folder 5: 13)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin D., 1925-1929 (Folder 5: 14)
    - Roosevelt, Theodore, 1924-1933 (Folder 5: 15)
    - Storrow, Helen, 1930-1935 (Folder 5: 16)
    - Tigert, John James, 1924-1929 (Folder 5: 17)
    - United States. Department of Agriculture. Bureau of Home Economics, 1929 (Folder 5: 18)
    - United States. Public Health Service, 1924-1932 (Folder 5: 19)
    - Wilder, George W., 1924-1931 (Box-folder 6: 1)
    - Winter, Thomas G., Mrs., 1924-1929 (Folder 6: 2)
    - Work, Hubert, 1924-1929 (Folder 6: 3)
  - Form letters sent to members, 1924-1927 (Folder 6: 4)
  - Lists
    - Advisory Council members, 1929 (Folder 6: 5)
    - States, cities, and counties represented by Better Homes chairmen, 1931 July (Folder 6: 6)
  - Speeches and writings
    - Abbott, Grace, 1924 (Folder 6: 7)
    - Gries, John M., 1923 (Folder 6: 8)
    - Hoover, Herbert C., 1921-1927 (Folder 6: 9)
    - Ihlder, John, n.d. (Folder 6: 10)
- Ray Lyman Wilbur File, 1920-1945. (Box 7, Box 7-9)
  Correspondence, memoranda, reports, speeches and writings, and other material of R. L. Wilbur as Chairman of the Board of Directors. Arranged alphabetically by physical form
  - Correspondence
    - General
      - 1920-1928 (Folder 7: 1)
      - 1929-1935 (Folder 7: 2)
      - 1933 (Folder 7: 3-4)
      - 1934 (Folder 7: 5)
      - 1935 (Folder 7: 6)
      - 1935-1945 (Box-folder 8: 1)
    - Cheney, Charles H., 1931 (Folder 8: 2)
    - Ford, James
      - 1925-1932 (Folder 8: 3)
      - 1932-1933 (Folder 8: 4)
  - Speeches and writings, 1927-1933 (Folder 8: 5)
  - Subject file
    - Board of Directors, 1929-1934 (Folder 8: 6)
    - Campaigns
      - 1928-1929 (Folder 8: 7)
      - 1929-1930 (Folder 8: 8)
      - 1930-1931 (Box-folder 9: 1)
      - 1931-1933 (Folder 9: 2)
    - Housing - United States, 1929-1938 (Folder 9: 3)
    - Presentation to Rockefeller Foundation, 1930 January (Folder 9: 4)
    - Reorganization planning for Better Homes in America, 1929 (Folder 9: 5)
- Personnel File, 1924-1933. (Box 9-10)
  Correspondence, memoranda, reports, and other material relating to the operations of the Personnel Department. Arranged alphabetically by subject
  - Better Homes chairmen at President's Conference on Home Building and Home Ownership, 1931 December 2-5 (Folder 9: 6)
  - Salaries, 1933 (Folder 9: 7)
  - Staff
    - General (Folder 9: 8)
    - General (Box-folder 10: 1-2)
    - Connor, Julia
      - General (Folder 10: 3-4)
      - Correspondence with James Ford
        - 1924-1930 (Folder 10: 5)
        - 1931 (Folder 10: 6)
      - Speeches and writings, 1925 (Folder 10: 7-8)
    - Lewton, Blanche (Folder 10: 9)
    - Liston, Katherine (Folder 10: 10)
    - Surette, Thomas (Folder 10: 11)
- Correspondence, 1922-1935. (Box 11-22)
  Letters, sent and received by the BHA staff, arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent
  - General (Box 11)
    - Foreign letters
      - 1924-1926 (Folder 11: 1)
      - 1927-1928 (Folder 11: 2)
      - 1929-1933 (Folder 11: 3)
    - Topical file
      - African-American issues, 1929-1930 (Folder 11: 4)
      - Architectural information, 1925-1932 (Folder 11: 5)
      - Conventions, 1932 (Folder 11: 6)
      - Housing, 1924-1932 (Folder 11: 7)
      - New York Low-Cost Housing Exhibit, 1934 (Folder 11: 8)
      - Politics, 1928 (Folder 11: 9)
  - Adams, Thompson and Fry, 1933 (Folder 12: 1)
  - Agricultural Commission of the American Bankers Association, 1927 (Folder 12: 2)
  - Alabama Power Company, 1926 (Folder 12: 3)
  - American Art Bureau
    - 1924-1928
    - 1929-1931 (Folder 12: 5)
  - American Automobile Association, 1925-1928 (Folder 12: 6)
  - American Child Health Association
    - 1929-1931 (Folder 12: 7)
    - 1932-1934 (Folder 12: 8)
  - American Civil Association (James Harlean)
    - 1924-1928 (Folder 12: 9)
    - 1929-1933 (Folder 12: 10)
  - American Face Brick Association, 1924-1926 (Folder 12: 11)
  - American Federation of Arts, 1933-34 (Folder 12: 12)
  - American Home Bureau, 1922-1927 (Folder 12: 13)
  - American Institute of Architects, 1923-1932 (Folder 12: 14)
  - American Library Association, 1929-1933 (Box-folder 13: 1)
  - American Optical Company, 1926 (Folder 13: 2)
  - American Radiator Company, 1926-1930 (Folder 13: 3)
  - American Red Cross, 1934 (Folder 13: 4)
  - American Relief Administration
    - General, 1927-1929 (Folder 13: 5)
    - Children's Fund
      - 1929-1932 (Folder 13: 6)
      - 1932-1935 (Folder 13: 7)
  - American Society of Agricultural Engineers, 1924-1929 (Folder 13: 8)
  - American Stove Company, 1923-1927 (Folder 13: 9)
  - American War Mothers, 1925-1926 (Folder 13: 10)
  - Americana Corporation, 1924-1930 (Folder 13: 11)
  - Apatow, J. J., 1926 (Folder 13: 12)
  - Architects Small House Service Bureau
    - General, 1925-1932 (Folder 13: 13)
    - Holden, Arthur C., 1925-1931 (Folder 13: 14)
    - Jones, Robert T., 1929-1932 (Box-folder 14: 1)
    - Lake Division architects, 1928 (Folder 14: 2)
    - Mountain Division architects, 1928-1930 (Folder 14: 3)
    - New England Division architects, 1927-1930 (Folder 14: 4)
    - North Central Division architects, 1928-29 (Folder 14: 5)
    - North Pacific Division architects, 1928-1931 (Folder 14: 6)
    - Potomac Division architects, 1928 (Folder 14: 7)
    - Shearer, Alan, 1931-1932 (Folder 14: 8)
    - South Central Division architects, 1928-1929 (Folder 14: 9)
    - Subscriptions, 1930 (Folder 14: 10)
  - Armstrong Cork Company, 1924-1925 (Folder 14: 11)
  - Associated General Contractors of America, 1930 (Folder 14: 12)
  - Associated Metal Lath Manufacturers, 1923-1930 (Folder 14: 13)
  - Barton, Durstine and Osborne, Inc., 1924-1926 (Folder 14: 14)
  - Benedict, P. F., 1933 (Folder 14: 15)
  - Better Homes and Property Service, 1924-1925 (Folder 14: 16)
  - Better Housing Institute, 1934-1935 (Folder 14: 17)
  - Bing Company, 1927 (Folder 14: 18)
  - Bowser Service Corporation, 1927 (Folder 14: 19)
  - Boy Scouts of America, 1933 (Folder 14: 20)
  - Building Age and National Builder Company, 1924-1928 (Folder 14: 21)
  - Building Developer, 1927-1929 (Folder 14: 22)
  - Camp Fire Girls, Inc., 1924-1933 (Box-folder 15: 1)
  - Capper's magazine, 1924-1930 (Folder 15: 2)
  - Carnegie Foundation, 1925-1933 (Folder 15: 3)
  - Celotex Company, 1927 (Folder 15: 4)
  - Central Advertising Company, 1925 (Folder 15: 5)
  - Certified Building Registry, 1929-1930 (Folder 15: 6)
  - Chamber of Commerce of the United States, 1928-1932 (Folder 15: 7)
  - Champion Hardware Company, 1926 (Folder 15: 8)
  - Character Education Institute, 1922-1928 (Folder 15: 9)
  - Child Study Association, 1925-1927 (Folder 15: 10)
  - The Children's Foundation, 1925 (Folder 15: 11)
  - Common Brick Manufacturers' Association, 1923-1925 (Folder 15: 12)
  - Concrete Lumber Corporation, 1926 (Folder 15: 13)
  - Contractors and Builders Exchange, 1933 (Folder 15: 14)
  - Coolidge, Calvin, 1922-1928 (Folder 15: 15)
  - Crane Company, 1930 (Folder 15: 16)
  - Doubleday, Doran and Company, 1924-1931 (Folder 15: 17)
  - Dow Chemical Company, 1926 (Box-folder 16: 1)
  - E. P. Dutton and Company, 1925 (Folder 16: 2)
  - Equitable Life Insurance Society, 1925 (Folder 16: 3)
  - Esmond Mills, 1926-1929 (Folder 16: 4)
  - Falk Foundation, 1930-1931 (Folder 16: 5)
  - Farrar Lumber Company, 1926 (Folder 16: 6)
  - Federal Board for Vocational Education, 1927-1931 (Folder 16: 7)
  - First Savings Bank, Greenville, South Carolina, 1924 (Folder 16: 8)
  - Flagg, Maurice I., 1926-1928 (Folder 16: 9)
  - Garden Club of America, 1925-1930 (Folder 16: 10)
  - General Education Board, New York City, 1929-1930 (Folder 16: 11)
  - General Electric Company, 1925-1926 (Folder 16: 12)
  - General Federation of Women's Clubs
    - 1924-1931 (Folder 16: 13)
    - 1925-1930 (Folder 16: 14)
  - Girl Scouts
    - 1925-1929 (Folder 16: 15)
    - 1929-1930 (Folder 16: 16)
    - 1929-1930 (Box-folder 17: 1)
    - 1930-1934 (Folder 17: 2)
  - Gladding Dry Goods Company, 1924 (Folder 17: 3)
  - The Glidden Companies, 1926 (Folder 17: 4)
  - The Grade Teacher, 1930 (Folder 17: 5)
  - Greyhound Vans, 1933 (Folder 17: 6)
  - Hardie, R. W., 1925 (Folder 17: 7)
  - Hearst's International, 1924-1925 (Folder 17: 8)
  - Holland's magazine, 1925-1930 (Folder 17: 9)
  - Home Designer, 1927-1928 (Folder 17: 10)
  - Home Economic News, 1930-1932 (Folder 17: 11)
  - Home Furnishers Digest, 1924 (Folder 17: 12)
  - Home Information Centers, 1930-1931 (Folder 17: 13)
  - The Homemaker, 1929 (Folder 17: 14)
  - Homes Harmonious, 1924 (Folder 17: 15)
  - Hoover, Herbert C., Mrs., 1924-1930 (Folder 17: 16)
  - Household Searchlight, 1928 (Folder 17: 17)
  - Howard Associates, 1933 (Folder 17: 18)
  - The Independent, 1925-1926 (Folder 17: 19)
  - Indiana Farmer's Guide, 1925 (Folder 17: 20)
  - Institute for Economic Research, 1930-1933 (Folder 17: 21)
  - International Education Board, 1926 (Folder 17: 22)
  - The Jewish Tribune, 1925 (Folder 17: 23)
  - Journal of Social Forces, 1924-1925 (Folder 17: 24)
  - Kiwanis Magazine, 1924 (Folder 17: 25)
  - Ladies' Home Journal, 1924-1930 (Folder 17: 26)
  - Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial, 1924-1929 (Folder 17: 27)
  - Lawrence, John D., 1927-1928 (Folder 17: 28)
  - Le Matin (Paris), 1924 (Folder 17: 29)
  - League for Accountancy in Government, 1926 (Folder 17: 30)
  - Lions International, 1925-1927 (Box-folder 18: 1)
  - Lippincott Company, Publishers, 1924-1931 (Folder 18: 2)
  - McCray Refrigerator Sales Corporation, 1926 (Folder 18: 3)
  - McDougall Domestic Science Kitchen Units, 1930 (Folder 18: 4)
  - McFarland, J. Horace, 1929-1935 (Folder 18: 5)
  - Maffitt and Gilpin Company, 1926 (Folder 18: 6)
  - The Man on the Floor, 1924 (Folder 18: 7)
  - Mandel Brothers, 1925 (Folder 18: 8)
  - Mann, Clyde, 1922-1931 (Folder 18: 9)
  - Mason City Brick and Tile Company, 1925 (Folder 18: 10)
  - Masonic Service Association, 1924 (Folder 18: 11)
  - Massachusetts Housing Association, 1931-1932 (Folder 18: 12)
  - Massey Concrete Products Corporation, 1926 (Folder 18: 13)
  - Maxwelch Company, 1924 (Folder 18: 14)
  - Metropolitan Life Insurance Company, 1924-1929 (Folder 18: 15)
  - Mid-Week Pictorial, 1926-1929 (Folder 18: 16)
  - Mississippi Woman's Magazine, 1928-1929 (Folder 18: 17)
  - Mizner Industries Incorporated, 1927 (Folder 18: 18)
  - Modern Woodmen of America, 1925 (Folder 18: 19)
  - Monarch Home Service, 1926 (Folder 18: 20)
  - Montgomery Ward and Company, 1925 (Folder 18: 21)
  - Morgan Company, 1926 (Folder 18: 22)
  - Morgan Sash and Door Company, 1925 (Folder 18: 23)
  - Morgan Woodwork Organization, 1930 (Folder 18: 24)
  - Mother's Day International Association, 1924-1926 (Folder 18: 25)
  - Murphy Door Bed Company, 1924 (Folder 18: 26)
  - Murphy Varnish Company, 1924 (Folder 18: 27)
  - Murray, Daniel, Mrs., 1930 (Folder 18: 28)
  - Mutual Building and Loan Association, 1933 (Folder 18: 29)
  - The Nation, 1925 (Folder 18: 30)
  - The Nation's Health, 1925 (Folder 18: 31)
  - National Association of Colored Women, 1929-1930 (Folder 18: 32)
  - National Association of Home Founders, 1932 (Folder 18: 33)
  - National Association of Ice Industries, 1925-1928 (Folder 18: 34)
  - National Association of Real Estate Boards, 1923-1932 (Box-folder 19: 1)
  - National Association of the Industries, 1924 (Folder 19: 2)
  - National Builder, 1924 (Folder 19: 3)
  - National Builders Supply Association, 1925 (Folder 19: 4)
  - National Conference on the Renewal of Home Building, 1933 (Folder 19: 5)
  - National Congress of Parents and Teachers, 1924-1934 (Folder 19: 6-8)
  - National Council of '76, 1933 (Folder 19: 9)
  - National Council of Jewish Women, 1931 (Folder 19: 10)
  - National Education Association, 1923-1931 (Folder 19: 11)
  - National Electric Light Association, 1927 (Folder 19: 12)
  - The National Gleaner Forum, 1925 (Folder 19: 13)
  - National Home Retirement League, 1926 (Folder 19: 14)
  - National Information Bureau, 1927-1935 (Box-folder 20: 1)
  - National Motion Picture Bureau, 1925-1926 (Folder 20: 2)
  - National Municipal Review, 1932 (Folder 20: 3)
  - National Real Estate Journal, 1929 (Folder 20: 4)
  - National Retail Furniture Association, 1925-1929 (Folder 20: 5)
  - National Retail Lumber Dealer, 1924 (Folder 20: 6)
  - National Safety Council, 1927-1931 (Folder 20: 7)
  - National Urban League, 1926-1927 (Folder 20: 8)
  - The Nebraska Farmer, 1929-1930 (Folder 20: 9)
  - Needlework, 1924 (Folder 20: 10)
  - New York (State). Banking Department, 1924 (Folder 20: 11)
  - New York Foundation, 1933-1934 (Folder 20: 12)
  - New York State Teachers Association, 1926 (Folder 20: 13)
  - Nolen, John, 1926-1931 (Folder 20: 14)
  - Northeastern Retail Lumbermens Association, 1924 (Folder 20: 15)
  - Oklahoma Farmer-Stockman, 1928-1930 (Folder 20: 16)
  - Operative Builders Association of the District of Columbia, 1924 (Folder 20: 17)
  - Opportunity, 1931 (Folder 20: 18)
  - Outdoor Advertising Association, 1932-1934 (Folder 20: 19)
  - The Outlook, 1924 (Folder 20: 20)
  - Own Your Own Home, 1925-1927 (Folder 20: 21)
  - Pacific Ready Cut Homes, Incorporated, 1926 (Folder 20: 22)
  - Palmolive Company, 1924 (Folder 20: 23)
  - Peaslee, Horace W., 1925-1928 (Folder 20: 24)
  - Pennsylvania Farmer, 1925 (Folder 20: 25)
  - Philadelphia Housing Association, 1926-1931 (Folder 20: 26)
  - The Phonograph and Talking Machine Weekly, 1924 (Folder 20: 27)
  - Political Science Quarterly, 1927 (Folder 20: 28)
  - Prentice, Cornelia E., 1926-1927 (Folder 20: 29)
  - Promoter and Defender of Christian Homes, 1924 (Box-folder 21: 1)
  - Quaker Lace Company, 1924 (Folder 21: 2)
  - Renshaw School of Speech, 1933 (Folder 21: 3)
  - Retail Publishers, Incorporated, 1926 (Folder 21: 4)
  - Richardson, Inez, 1934-1935 (Folder 21: 5)
  - Richardson-Briggs Company, 1924-1928 (Folder 21: 6)
  - Richey, Lawrence (secretary to Herbert C. Hoover), 1929-1932 (Folder 21: 7)
  - Rickard, Edgar, 1929-1933 (Folder 21: 8)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1929-1930 (Folder 21: 9)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D., 1926-1933 (Folder 21: 10)
  - Rosenwald, Julius, 1925-1930 (Folder 21: 11)
  - Russell Sage Foundation, 1924-1934 (Folder 21: 12)
  - Russia Cement Company, 1926 (Folder 21: 13)
  - Saint Nicholas Magazine, 1929-1930 (Folder 21: 14)
  - The Scholastic, 1927-1930 (Folder 21: 15)
  - The Scientific Monthly, 1928-1929 (Folder 21: 16)
  - Scranton Electric Company, 1926 (Folder 21: 17)
  - Scranton Lace Company, 1924 (Folder 21: 18)
  - Shatts, W. Philip, 1924-1935 (Folder 21: 19)
  - Sierra Educational News, 1927-1928 (Folder 21: 20)
  - Silotco Products, Ltd., 1930-1931 (Folder 21: 21)
  - Sloane, Thomas M., 1927-1930 (Folder 21: 22)
  - South Bend Lumber Company, 1924 (Folder 21: 23)
  - Southern Agriculturalist, 1924-1931 (Folder 21: 24)
  - Southern Pine Association, 1927-1930 (Folder 21: 25)
  - The Sovereign Citizen, 1925-1928 (Folder 21: 26)
  - The Spectator (London), 1926 (Folder 21: 27)